### **AUGUSTUS HEPTIG**

Wells, ME 04090 | Phone: (207) 206 5175 | Email: gusheptig@gmail.com LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/augustus-h/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/augustus-h/</a> | GitHub github.com/gheptig | Portfolio: <a href="https://protected-harbor-06157.herokuapp.com/">https://protected-harbor-06157.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer willing to relocate with a background in business leveraging interest in problem solving and design into a role to provide a more efficient experience on the web. Able to collaborate with others to deliver written documents and other models of data to clients in a timely and effective manner. Ambitious and able to be methodical and bring worthwhile collaboration to any team providing valuable and worthwhile input and output.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Applications: React.js, Vue.js, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Bootstrap, React Bootstrap, Vue Bootstrap, Materialize.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Envira | Full-Stack Developer | Deployed Link: <a href="https://envira-bot.com/">https://envira-bot.com/</a> | Github Lin

Environmental application that utilizes an AI robot (Envira) to interact and deliver climate change information/data in a fun unique manner.

- Role: Worked on front and back end development of environmental event features that included
  the creation of events that were posted to SQL database, a search page utilizing Axios to request
  event data from database and render to a series of cards in a carousel using React-Bootstrap.
  Implemented UX using React-Router-DOM using parameters in URL to allow access and link
  information page to page based on user/event information.
- **Utilized**: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, AWS Amplify, AWS EC2, AWS Lex, AWS Polly, AWS S3, AWS Cognito, AWS Route 53, React Bootstrap.

# GamerEvolution | Full-Stack Developer | Deployed Link: <a href="https://fatidique-moliere-24500.herokuapp.com/index.html">https://fatidique-moliere-24500.herokuapp.com/index.html</a> | Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/gheptig/gamerevolution">https://github.com/gheptig/gamerevolution</a> Full-stack application that allows users to create a unique profile and build a social environment for all things related to video games.

- Role: Focused on front and back end development of "Game Search" page which consisted of a set of search inputs and filters on the UI to allow a user to either browse/search for multiple or specific games titles. Implemented rendered search result data to HTML page into a grid of cards built and styled with Bootstrap and CSS. Created user "Game Library" feature that saved user's favorite games by posting game information to SQL database based on user identification which could be later accessed and rendered back to a on their established user profile through jQuery AJAX get requests.
- Utilized: jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Passport.js, Bootstrap, MySQL, Sequelize, RAWG Video Game Database API.

Continued...

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

#### Movie Phood | Front-End Developer | Deployed Link: https://gheptig.github.io/movie-phood/ | Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/gheptig/movie-phood">https://github.com/gheptig/movie-phood</a>

Created for movie and food lovers alike, this is a front-end application that returns a movie/food/drink combination to a user based on their preferences and tastes.

- **Role:** Served as project/repository manager and developed a system using input from the user to make a series of jQuery AJAX get requests from a group of server side APIs related to movies, food, and drinks in order to generate a combination and then store the user's generated combination into the browser's local storage to then be rendered on a series of cards built and styled with Materialize.css.
- Utilized: ¡Query, Materialize.css, Postman, TheMovieDB API, TheCocktailDB API, and TheMealDB API.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Probate Assistant**

#### York County Probate Court (Remote)

2020 - Present

Meet and interview respondents regarding proposed proceedings concerning Guardianship and/or Conservatorship. Effectively serve and make clients aware of legal rights in a timely and accurate manner.

 Successfully document, assess, file, and submit written court appointed reports to be used by the Judge of Probate in the decision-making process.

#### **Deckhand**

2019 - 2020

**F/V Priorities** 

Perkins Cove, ME

Worked alongside ship captain with the general operation of the vessel. Performed vessel maintenance service that included cleaning, painting and basic mechanical repairs. Remained focused in a fast-paced commercial fishing environment and remained constantly alert under strenuous hours.

#### **Paraplanner**

2017 - 2019

James E. Lamb & Associates

Scarborough, ME

## (Ameriprise Financial)

Effectively assisted financial advisors in the preparation of written client financial planning/investment proposals and letters. Developed and maintained a checklist for tracking and organizing client financial plan engagements. Created and provided portfolio snapshots, investment research, and other models of financial data upon request by staff and clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of New Hampshire, Portsmouth, NH A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js, and React.js. 2020

Bachelor of Science, Finance: University of Maine, Orono, ME | Honors: cum laude. | 2017